People said we make christmas and i didn't understand what that was
有人说我们要"过圣诞"，我当时不明白这是什么意思。
Christmas morning a young lady came on her marsh tacky right ? that's a horse
圣诞节早晨，一个年轻女子骑着她的沼泽马来了——那是一种马。
Oh , she knocked on the door and said
她敲了敲门，说：
You come over to rehouse and you all make christmas
"你来我们家，大家一起过圣诞。"
And i got to a house and his ham
我到了那家，看到了火腿，
This chicken
还有鸡肉，
His green corn bread , nest beer and a little white cuz they call it
绿色的玉米面包、根汁啤酒，还有他们称之为白色的东西。
And then the man in that house said
然后那家的男主人说，
let's we take a walk
"我们去走走吧。"
And we went to somebody else's house and they say welcome
我们去了另一家，他们说"欢迎，
Go to the table and make christmas
到桌上来，一起过圣诞。"
And that day with this man
就这样和这个男人，
I went from house to house
我们挨家挨户地走，
And the man of that house would welcome us
每一家的男主人都热情欢迎我们，
We eat and dine and now with that man follow you
我们吃喝玩乐，走着走着，那个男人就跟上来了。
That man would join us
那个男人就加入了我们。
So then it would be three of you
后来就变成了三个人，
By the time and we got halfway through today
到了那天下午走了一半时，
It was about six or seven of us
我们已经有六七个人了，
And they were at various states of indebriation
大家都处于不同程度的醉意之中。
Yeah they would lit up
是的，大家都喝嗨了。
We went till late that night
我们一直走到深夜，
when the moon was out
月亮都出来了。
And the last house we had to go to
最后一家要去的，
They wanted to take a shortcut across the alligator pawn
他们想抄近路穿过鳄鱼塘。
Oh and you had to walk across this plane . ha ha ha
哦，你们得走过一块跳板，哈哈哈。
Cause you know you don't wanna wake up and get it
你懂的，谁也不想惊醒鳄鱼。
Yeah , they sent me across first
是啊，他们让我先过。
Well i made it all the way across that plank carefully
我小心翼翼地走过了整块跳板，
And got up on the hill
安全上了岸，
then every one of the others that came after me
结果后面每一个跟过来的人，
Fill in that they drking
都因为喝多了掉进了水里，
When they hit that water they almost walked on
一碰到水，他们几乎都走上去了，
Yeah , yeah
是是是。
Now get the bone that hill
大家都爬上了那个坡。
As we continued walking
我们继续往前走，
I noticed you had to go to every home
我注意到，你必须去到每一户人家，
so you couldn't be out of sorts with somebody
所以你不能跟任何人闹别扭。
And they'd make amends
大家就和解了。
Ain't any no use me to be mad with one another
彼此生气是没有意义的，
You know , that was childish and they would hog and makeup
那是幼稚的，大家就拥抱和好了。
and it was the most joyous time
那是我见过最欢乐的时光，
Because there was this resolution of conflict of hostility
因为那是一次化解矛盾与敌意的仪式，
And planning for the next year to begin in harmony
大家计划着在新的一年里和谐共处。
Yeah , a new year starting together
是的，大家一起迎接新年。
Yes
对。
And so i came to my understanding of making christmas
就这样，我终于明白了"过圣诞"的真正含义。
Mmmm
嗯。
Oh my army my army my army
哦，我的军队，我的军队，我的军队……
Crossf my army my army army
跨越我的军队，我的军队……
Cross sou my army my army
越过南方，我的军队，我的军队……
my my cramy army . my army
我的军队，我亲爱的军队。